Contact

kbeatty2017@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/krystal-beatty-msn-rn-a64693113 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Telemetry Surgery

Krystal Beatty, MSN, RN

Quality Outcomes/Performance Improvement Specialist at Houston Methodist

Houston, Texas

Summary

Methodical and process-oriented nursing professional with a wide range of experience from bedside acute care to quality performance improvement. Proven experience in leading teams at both the micro and macro system levels. In pursuit of a Clinical Specialist opportunity to apply clinical expertise and strategy by delivering transformative solutions to improve workflows, population health, patient and provider satisfaction, and reduce costs.

Experience

Houston, Texas

Houston Methodist Quality Outcomes/Performance Improvement Specialist September 2017 - Present (2 years 10 months)

- Facilitate process improvement initiatives by using evidence based practice and performing targeted audits to gather and analyze data, whilst using lean methodologies such as PDSA, process flow mapping, and A3 Forms
- Quality Consultant for nursing units by disseminating monthly quality metric dashboards used to identify opportunities for improvement, initiate performance improvement projects, standardize practice, and lead educational in-services and training for bedside staff
- Care Coordinator- Clinical leader identifying opportunities to improve throughput and patient experience
- Subject Matter Expert (SME) to hospital wide Venous Thromboembolic (VTE) prevention initiative:
- Project Manager Coordinator for strategic inter-professional VTE Leadership meetings, collaborative efforts with supply chain and nurse education, direct nursing VTE prevention efforts hospital wide, improve workflow and liaison between VTE Champion team and leadership
- Chair, VTE Champions Committee Launched

CHI St. Luke's Health - Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center Registered Nurse

January 2015 - April 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Houston, Texas Area

- RN III/Charge Nurse and Preceptor to students and graduate nurses
- Project Manager Improved nurse compliance rate with central line care bundle from 65% to 100% over a five month period
- Communication Champion Mentored staff, performed in-services on effective team communication, and conflict management
- Spearheaded staff engagement/resilience programs such as: nurse week activities and educational board
- Nurse Training Validator for Bi-Annual Hospital Skills Fair educated bedside staff in skills such as physical assessment, safe mobility, infection prevention practices and supply management

MedStaff

Travel Nurse

September 2014 - December 2014 (4 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Worked as a registered nurse on a telemetry and progressive care unit.

American Mobile Healthcare

Travel Nurse

September 2013 - August 2014 (1 year)

Greensboro/Winston-Salem, North Carolina Area; Baltimore, MD; Houston, TX

Worked as a Registered Nurse in each hospital for 13 weeks each. Areas of specialty included Trauma, Telemetry and Otolaryngology.

Chandler Regional Medical Center Registered Nurse

July 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 2 months)

- Registered Nurse cross trained on progressive care, medical surgical and transplant floors
- Charge Nurse- responsible for creating daily staff assignments, acuity assessment, providing resource assistance and conflict resolution
- Project Manager orchestrated multidisciplinary team of senior leadership, frontline staff, sales vendors, and supply chain management to modify central line packaging to improve workflow, resource utilization, and hospital cost efficiency
- Analyzed and adjusted employee schedules to meet unit staffing needs

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston Master of Science in Nursing (MSN), Leadership and Administration (2015 - 2017)

University of Kentucky
Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2007 - 2011)